project-a.com 2017-11-15

# Privacy Policy | Project A | The Operational VC

In the following, we would like to inform you about the collection, processing and utilization of personal data within our website. The cautious handling of personal information is a matter of great concern to us. When processing your personal data, we comply with the legal requirements and protect your privacy.

You can print or save this document by using the usual functionality of your browser (typically save file as). You can also download and archive this file by clicking [here](https://www.project-a.com/content/privacy-policy/data-protection-policy-project-a.pdf). In order to open the PDF-document you will need the program Adobe Reader [www.adobe.de](http://www.adobe.de/), which comes at no cost, or similar programs, which can open the PDF-format.

 _1\. Person of Contact and Possibility of Opposition_  
Contact person and so called responsible body for the collection, processing and utilization of your personal data according to the Federal Data Protection Act, as well as a service provider in the sense of the Telemedia Act is the

Project A Services GmbH & Co. KG  
Julie-Wolfthorn-Straße 1  
10115 Berlin

E-Mail: [datenschutz@project-a.com](https://www.project-a.com/mailto:%20datenschutz@project-a.com)  
Fon +49 30 340 606 300  
Fax: +49 30 340 606 399  
If you wish to object to the collection, processing or use of your data as a whole, or for individual measures according to this data protection policy, you can send your objection by e-mail, fax or letter to the above-mentioned contact data.

 _2\. Collection, processing and utilization of personal data_  
If you use our website or interact with our website (for example fill in and submit the contact form), we collect, process and use personal data.

 **2.1. Personal Data**  
Personal data refers to data about the objective or personal affairs of a specified or specifiable natural person. This includes particularly information that allow for conclusions regarding your identity, for example your name, your telephone number, your address or e-mail address. Statistical data that we collect, for example, when you visit our website and which cannot be directly linked to your person, do not come under the concept of the personal date.

 **2.2. Informative Use**  
In the case of the mere informative use of the website, we do not collect any personal data, except for the data transmitted by your browser to enable you to visit the website. These are:

•IP address  
• Date and time of the request  
• Time zone difference to Greenwich Mean Time (GMT)  
• Content of the request (concrete page)  
• Access Status / HTTP status code  
• The amount of data transferred  
• Website from which the request comes  
• Browser  
• Operating system and its surface  
• Language and version of the browser.

The IP addresses of the users are deleted or anonymised after the end of the usage. In the case of anonymization, the IP addresses are changed in such a way that the individual details about personal or objective affairs can no longer, or only with a disproportionate amount of time, costs and labor power, be assigned to a specified or specifiable natural person. The data in the so-called log files are evaluated anonymously by us in order to further improve the Project A website and to make it more user-friendly, as well as to find and correct errors more quickly. In addition, they are used to control the server capacities, in order to be able to provide corresponding data volumes in case of need.

 _2.3. Disclosure of Data to Third Parties_  
The transfer of the data collected by Project A to third parties only takes place if this is necessary for the purpose of contract processing or settlement, or if you have previously given your consent. The data thus provided may only be used by our service providers to fulfil their task. These were carefully selected by us and commissioned in writing. They are bound by our instructions and regularly checked by us. Any other use of the information is not permitted and is likewise not carried out by any of our service providers.

 _3\. Cookies_  
Cookies are small files that are stored on your data carrier and store certain settings and data for exchange with our system via your browser. Cookies cannot run programs or transmit viruses to your computer. They aim at making the Internet offer more user-friendly and effective.

Basically, two different types of cookies exist, so-called session cookies, which are deleted, as soon as you close your browser (= end of the session) and temporary / permanent cookies, which are stored for an extended period or unlimited on your data carrier. This storage helps us to design our website and makes it easier for you to use it, by storing specific entries so that you do not have to repeat them all the time.  
You may delete the cookies in the security settings of your browser at any time and configure your browser settings according to your needs (for example, accepting third party cookies or rejecting all cookies). As a rule, you will be shown how to reject new cookies and delete already received ones in the menu bar of your web browser. However, we would point out that you may not be able to use all the features of our website.

 _3.1. Cookies at Project A_  
Most of the cookies we use are session cookies and are automatically deleted from your hard drive after the end of the browser session. In addition, we use permanent cookies that remain on your hard drive. During a subsequent visit the browser automatically recognizes that you were already with us and also, which inputs and settings you prefer. These cookies will be stored on your hard drive and will be deleted by itself after the specified time.

The cookies used by us are not assigned to any specific person and therefore not assigned to you. When the cookie is activated, an identification number is assigned to it. An assignment of your personal data to this identification number is not possible at any time. It does not store your name or similar data that would allow the allocation of a cookie to you.

 **4\. Web Analysis**  
_4.1. Google Analytics_  
This website uses Google Analytics, a web analytics service provided by Google, Inc., 1600 Amphitheater Parkway, Mountain View, CA 94043, USA ("Google"). Google Analytics uses cookies to analyze the user behavior on websites. The information generated by cookies about the use of this website is transferred to a Google server in the USA and stored there. However, your IP address is shortened before the usage statistics are evaluated, so that no conclusions can be drawn about your identity. Hereto, Google Analytics was extended on our website with the code "anonymizeIp" to ensure an anonymous capture of IP addresses.

Google will use the information obtained by the cookies to evaluate your use of the website, to compile reports on the website activity for the website operators and to provide further services connected with the use of the website and the Internet. Google may also transfer this information to third parties, provided this is required by law or if third parties process this data on behalf of Google.

You can configure your browser to discard cookies, or you can track the data generated by the cookie and related to your use of this website (including your IP address) to Google, as well as the processing of that data by Google by downloading and installing the [browser plug-in](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=de).

As an alternative to the browser add-on or within browsers on mobile devices, you can set an opt-out cookie to prevent Google Analytics from being tracked within this site in the future. The opt-out cookie only works in the browser and only for this domain. If you delete your cookies in this browser, you must click this link again.

For more information about Google and privacy, see the [data protection overview](https://support.google.com/analytics/answer/6004245?hl=de) and the [data protection policy](http://www.google.de/intl/de/policies/privacy/).

 _4.2. Google Tag Manager_  
To manage our websites and to incorporate cookie-based technologies, we use the service Tag manager, which is offered by Google Inc., 1600 Amphitheater Parkway, Mountain View, CA 94043, USA ("Google"). To do this, each time you access one of our websites, your IP address is transferred to a Google server, which could be located in the USA. The IP address is not stored by Google as part of the Tag manager service and is only used to integrate the technologies that are managed by the Tag manager. The Tag manager itself does not set cookies.

 _4.3. Facebook Custom Audiences_  
We also use "Custom Audiences" from Facebook Inc., 1601 S. California Ave, Palo Alto, CA 94304, USA ("Facebook"). When you visit our website, a connection is established between your browser and the Facebook server. This gives Facebook the information that our website has visited from your IP address. If you are a Facebook member, Facebook can link this information to your Facebook profile, provided that you do not disprove this in the privacy settings of your Facebook account, and use it to target Facebook ads.

For detailed information on how your data is collected and used through Facebook and your rights and opportunities, see the Facebook privacy policy at the URL [facebook.com/about/privacy](https://www.facebook.com/about/privacy).

If you do not want Facebook to link the captured information to your Facebook profile, you can deactivate this function at the URL at any time [facebook.com/settings/?tab=ads](https://www.facebook.com/settings/?tab=ads).

 **5\. Social Media Plugins**  
_5.1. Facebook-Plugins_  
On our pages, plugins from the social network Facebook Inc., 1 Hacker Way, Menlo Park, CA 94025, USA are integrated. The Facebook plugins recognize you through the Facebook logo or the "Like-Button" on our site. An overview of the Facebook plugins can be found here: [developers.facebook.com/docs/plugins](http://developers.facebook.com/docs/plugins) .

When you visit our pages, the plug-in creates a direct connection between your browser and the Facebook server. Facebook thereby gets the information that you have visited our webpage with your IP address. If you click the Facebook "Like button" while you are logged in to your Facebook account, you can link the content of our pages to your Facebook profile. This allows Facebook to associate the visit of our pages with your user account. We would like to point out that as a provider of the pages we are not aware of the content of the transmitted data, as well as the use by Facebook. For more information, see Facebook's Privacy Statement [de-de.facebook.com/policy.php](http://de-de.facebook.com/policy.php). If you do not want Facebook to associate the visit of our pages with your Facebook user account, please log out of your Facebook user account.

 _5.2. Twitter_  
Functions of the Twitter service are integrated on our sites. These features are offered by Twitter Inc., 1355 Market Street, Suite 900, San Francisco, CA 94103, USA. By using Twitter and the "Re-Tweet" function, the pages you visit are linked to your Twitter account and shared with other users. This data is also transmitted to Twitter.  
We would like to point out that as a provider of the pages we are not aware of the content of the transmitted data as well as their use by Twitter. For more information, see Twitter's Privacy Statement at <http://twitter.com/privacy>.  
Your privacy settings on Twitter can be found in the account settings at [twitter.com/account/settings](http://twitter.com/account/settings).

 **6\. Google Maps**  
This website uses the Google Maps service from Google Inc., 1600 Amphitheater Parkway, Mountain View, CA 94043, USA ("Google"). In order for the Google map material, which we use, to be included and displayed in your web browser, your web browser must be connected to a Google server, which may be in the US, when you open the contact page. This gives Google the information that the contact page of our website has been opened from the IP address of your device. For more information, see the [Terms of use of Google Maps](https://www.google.com/intl/de_US/help/terms_maps.html).

 **7\. Data Security**  
We maintain up-to-date technical measures to ensure data security, in particular to protect your personal data from damages through data transfer and knowledge leakages to third-parties. These are adapted to the latest state of the art.

 **8\. Right of Access**  
According to the Federal Data Protection Act, our users have, amongst others, right to free information about their stored data and, where appropriate, a right to rectify, block or delete data.

We take the protection of your data very seriously. If you would like information about your stored data or further information regarding this privacy statement, please send your inquiry by e-mail or by post to the contact details mentioned above (see section 1).

 _Last update: May 2017_
